# **Fabrice Harel-Canada**

□ (+1) 954-805-5735 | ■ fabricehc@cs.ucla.edu | 🌴 fabrice.harel-canada.com | 🖸 fabriceyhc

### **Biography**

I am a computer science PhD student at UCLA where I am part of the Software Evolution and Analysis Lab and advised by Miryung Kim. I also work with Violet Peng in the PLUS Lab and Quanquan Gu in the Statistical Machine Learning Lab. My research aims at developing new techniques for training, testing, and evaluating ML systems. Previously, this has entailed devising novel adversarial attacks, investigating test metrics like neuron coverage for deep learning models, and proposing sibylvariant transformations to improve model generalization and robustness. My current projects span two distinct areas: a) developing fine-grained data lineage to support the creation of automated data augmentation policies and data exploration; b) producing reference-free evaluation metrics to measure the diversity and engagingness of natural language generation systems.

### Education

### University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA)

PHD | COMPUTER SCIENCE

- 3.92 / 4.00 GPA
- Majors: Software Engineering + Artificial Intelligence
- · Minor: Data Science Computing

#### University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA)

MS | COMPUTER SCIENCE

• Major: Artificial Intelligence

• Thesis: Is Neuron Coverage a Meaningful Measure for Testing Deep Neural Networks?

### University of Florida (UF)

BS | Business Administration

Aug 2008 - May 2012

- Majors: Management + Information Systems and Operations Management
- Minors: Entrepreneurship + Finance
- Thesis: The Viability of the Student-Run Housing Cooperative: A Case Study of the Cooperative Living Organization

### **Publications**

SIBYLVARIANT TRANSFORMATIONS FOR ROBUST TEXT CLASSIFICATION

Fabrice Harel-Canada, Muhammad Ali Gulzar, Nanyun Peng and Miryung Kim, in Findings of the Association for Computational Linquistics: ACL 2022, pages 1771-1788, Dublin, Ireland. Association for Computational Linguistics.

IS NEURON COVERAGE A MEANINGFUL MEASURE FOR TESTING DEEP NEURAL NETWORKS?

Fabrice Harel-Canada, Lingxiao Wang, Muhammad Ali Gulzar, Quanquan Gu and Miryung Kim, in Proc of ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE), Sacramento, California, USA, 2020.

Findings of ACL 2022

Advisor: Miryung Kim

Advisor: Miryung Kim

Sept 2018 - Dec 2019

Jan 2020 - Jun 2023

Acceptance Rate: 37 %

ESEC/FSE 2020

Acceptance Rate: 28 %

### Research Experience \_\_\_\_\_

GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCHER

### **University of California, Los Angeles**

Supervisor: Miryung Kim June 2019 - present

- · Developing automated evaluation metrics for natural language generation systems e.g. diversity, engagement
- Designed a new class of sibylvariant data transformations, releasing an open source tool for the community [Sibyl]
- · Evaluated the reliability of testing metrics for deep learning
- Developed diversity-promoting extensions to adversarial attack algorithms

#### **University of California, Los Angeles**

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

• Conducted LDA topic modeling and phrase-level sentiment analysis using BERT transformers on millions of Amazon and Glassdoor product / employer reviews

Supervisor: Judson Caskey

July 2020 - Oct 2020

FABRICE HAREL-CANADA · CV MAY 31, 2022

### **Professional Experience**

#### **Axenzi Consultants**

CEO Oct 2018 - present

· Helping clients to plan and implement technology projects - specs, devops, application development, and database development

#### **University of California, Los Angeles**

Supervisor: Miryung Kim

TEACHING ASSISTANT, CS 130: SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sept 2020 - Dec 2020

· Developed teaching materials, activities, and exam questions that reinforced the lectures and gauged conceptual proficiency.

Verox Tech Supervisor: Michael Simhai

PROJECT MANAGER + DEVELOPER TEAM LEAD

July 2015 - Sept 2018

- Designed and successfully launched a smarter insurance app by building, motivating, and guiding a team of 23
- Contributed 100s of check-ins, primarily consisting of C# Web APIs and database tables, triggers, sprocs, and T-SQL scripts
- Designed and implemented a 3-system legacy data migration
- Responsible for producing, coordinating and reviewing nearly every aspect of the SDLC:
  - code reviews and code optimization
  - requirements and spec generation
  - database design + SSIS + SSRS
  - technical documentation
  - UI design standards + product design
  - build and deployment scripts

### **People's Trust Insurance**

Supervisor: Scott Thompson

BUSINESS + DATA ANALYST

Dec 2012 - Sept 2018

- · Go-to data expert for executives to produce hundreds of reports and analyses for pivotal decision making at the executive level
- Developed numerous front-end / back-end application features that were successfully deployed into production to automate tedious and time-intensive workflows
- Performed continuous requirements gathering & demos with business stakeholders to support 60+ sprints of development for both applications and business intelligence teams, including the transition to a new policy and claim management system

#### **Cooperative Living Organization**

President Dec 2010 – May 2012

- · Appointed and oversaw the performance of 17 managers who were responsible for executing the policies and procedures I developed
- Increased house occupancy from 60 residents to full capacity (80) and increased net income 57% while expanding services & activities for residents

### **Skills**

**Programming** sql, python, java, c#, ling, html, css, js, scala, problog, prolog, LTEX

**Frameworks** pytorch, tensorflow, keras, spark, numpy, pandas, scipy, sklearn, opencv, matplotlib, seaborn **Tools** ssms, ssis, ssrs, tfs, azure devops, visual studio, excel, aws, gcp, exchange server, mogups

### Selected Coursework

2022	Natural Language Generation, CS 269	UCLA
2022	Automated Testing 4 Data Systems, CS 239	UCLA
2021	Large-Scale Data Mining, EC 219	UCLA
2021	Large-Scale Social and Complex Networks, EC 232E	UCLA
2020	Reinforcement Learning, EC 239AS	UCLA
2020	Machine Learning Algorithms, CS 260	UCLA
2020	Probabilistic Programming, CS 267A	UCLA
2019	Neural Networks and Deep Learning, EC 239AS	UCLA
2019	Natural Language Processing, CS 269	UCLA
2019	ML Testing and Debugging, CS 239	UCLA
2018	Advanced Data + Knowledge Bases, CS 240B	UCLA

May 31, 2022 Fabrice Harel-Canada · CV 2

### Honors & Awards

2019	Magna Cum Laude, 3.90 / 4.00 GPA	UCLA
2012	Magna Cum Laude, 3.85 / 4.00 GPA	University of Florida
2008 - 2012	Recipient, Bright Futures Academic Scholarship	University of Florida
2011 - 2012	Recipient, Anderson Scholar with Distinction	University of Florida

## Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

2020-2021	Mentor, Queers in STEM	Los Angeles, CA
2019	Volunteer, TreePeople	Los Angeles, CA
2018	<b>Volunteer</b> , Gay for Good (G4G)	Los Angeles, CA
2017	Volunteer, Los Angeles LGBT Center	Los Angeles, CA
2014	Volunteer, Stonewall Pride	Wilton Manors, FL
2009	Volunteer Counselor, CDS Interfaith Youth Shelter	Gainesville, FL
2009	Co-founder, Editor, Contributor, Florida Inquiry Journal	Gainesville, FL
2009 - 2010	Volunteer, Habitat for Humanity	Fort Lauderdale, FL
2008 - 2012	Member, UF Entrepreneurship Club	Gainesville, FL